# Emilio José Degiovanni

22+ years of experience. 7 years as Frontend, and 15 years as fullstack. My skills: leadership, team player, communication, mentorship, supervising, collaboration, problem-solving, adaptability, planning, critical thinking, attention on details.

"We develop software like we navigate a ship: with a clear plan, communication, and respect, we reach our destination together."

Alfredo Terzaga 5059 ph2 Córdoba, Argentina - CP:5008 (549) 351 216 8017 emiliodeg@gmail.com github.com/emiliodeg developtus.com

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **EPAM**, Princeton, NJ, USA (Remote)— Frontend Engineer

March 2024 - Present

Migrating applications made in Angular & Material v13 to v17. Refactoring to improve performance, reusability, and good practices on private libraries and applications. Coding review. Adding unit, integration, and e2e testing, Jest & Cypress. Azure CICD, Jira. Implementing signals. *Healthcare industry*.

## Byte Factory, Spain (Remote)— Frontend Lead

November 2023 - March 2024

Lead the frontend team. Mentored junior team members. Refactored components, services, directives, pipes, and reactive forms. Implemented authorization and authentication security layers. We worked with Angular 16, Typescript/JavaScript, RxJs, NgRx, API & BFF, Unit and integration test, Jira, Gitlab, Docker, Azure. *Retail industry*.

## **Double Nines**, Florida USA (Remote) — Frontend Lead

June 2022 - November 2023

Developed a private component library from Figma, and based on Kendo. Released with documentation, storybook, and testing.

Lead a frontend team. Started working with Angular 13, last release v15. Designed and implemented micro frontends infrastructure handled with Webpack Module Federation. App State with NgRx. Okta for authentication. Authorization with directives and guards. AWS.

Coached junior frontenders. Logistics industry.

# AquivaLabs, Florida, USA (Remote)— Frontend Engineer

January 2022-May 2022

Worked with Angular v8, Material and NGRX, mainly fixing bugs, and writing unit test. Developed new small features. *Insurance insdustry*.

# Cognizant Softvision, Argentine (Remote)— Frontend Lead

November 2020-December 2021

Lead the frontend team on a human resources platform based on Angular 9+ and Material, NGXS as application state, three.js, jasmine for unit testing. Main code reviewer.

Lead Angular technical interviewer of new candidates for the company.

Worked as frontend lead on a payment application. Developed a solution to manage internal users, customer clients, and payments.

#### **SKILLS**

Angular v4-18 TypeScript/JavaScript RxJS, NgRx/NgXs API/GraphQL/Websocket Material/Kendo/PrimeNG SCSS, Bootstrap/Tailwind HTML 5 semantic Jest/Jasmine/Storybook Cypress/Playwright Webpack/Esbuild/MFE Kubernetes & Docker Git/CICD AWS, Azure SCRUM/Kanban PHP 4+ Phalcon 3+ MySQL/MariaDB/Redis Apache/Nginx

## **LEARNING**

MERN stack + GraphQL at Helsinki University

## **LANGUAGES**

English C1 Spanish native

### **PERSONAL FREE TIME**

Family & friends, cycling, swimming, cooking, reading, dancing

# **Globant,** Argentine (on site) — Frontend Engineer & Lead

August 2019-November 2020

Working on several projects based on Angular 8+ and Material. Assigned to Ernest & Young. Code reviewer, coaching of junior frontenders. Created a guide of good practices and clean coding. Unit and integration tests with Jest. E2e with Selenium. Jira, and Azure. Scrum and Kanban. D3.js, Photoshop, SCSS, RestAPI.

Legal, contracts, and taxes industry

# Freelancer, Argentine — Fullstack

2002 - August 2019

I started as a professional fullstack developer in 2002. All my work was based on PHP (Zend and Phalcon frameworks), MySQL, Apache/Nginx over backend and HTML, CSS and Javascript with jQuery over frontend, upto I started with Angular v4. I developed many systems and websites, some relevant projects were

- Learny Online Argentine 2016-2019
  End-to-end development of an online e-learning platform
  Backend and frontend development
  APIs: Google, Facebook, PayPal and Vimeo
- <u>Lettersystems</u> Argentine 2014-2019
  Development of an application for client, project and budget management
  Backend and frontend development
- Advanced Architecture Contest Spain 2009-2019
  System of annual competitions for architects
  Template implementation
  Management of information pages, participants and awards

### **OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS**

## **Phacon** — PHP Full Stack Framework delivered as an extension

I spend time helping with this project mainly with Spanish documentation, writing unit tests and developing some new features or fixing bugs.

### **EDUCATION**

**National Technological University,** Córdoba Argentine — *Information systems engineering* 

2002 - 2006 Incomplete

**Catholic University of Córdoba,** Córdoba Argentine — *Information systems engineering* 

2000 - 2001 Incomplete